<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Demo | Mashkov I.E.</title>
    <link>http://localhost:1313/en/category/demo/</link>
      <atom:link href="http://localhost:1313/en/category/demo/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <description>Demo</description>
    <generator>Hugo Blox Builder (https://hugoblox.com)</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Fri, 10 May 2024 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <image>
      <url>http://localhost:1313/media/icon_hu0b7a4cb9992c9ac0e91bd28ffd38dd00_9727_512x512_fill_lanczos_center_3.png</url>
      <title>Demo</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/en/category/demo/</link>
    </image>
    
    <item>
      <title>How was my week? Part 4</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/en/post/post7_last-week/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 10 May 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/en/post/post7_last-week/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;nothing-interesting-happened-in-my-life&#34;&gt;Nothing interesting happened in my life&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In fact, it is. In the Warframe I&amp;rsquo;m going to craft Nidus, Sarina, Chrome, Nix and Titania. However, next week I will have both a control on mathematical analysis and a colloquium on analytical geometry, which is sad, frankly&amp;hellip;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How was my week? Part 3</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/en/post/post5_last-week/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 30 Apr 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/en/post/post5_last-week/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;monday&#34;&gt;Monday&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Two weeks have passed since the last recording for the past week, I received Gauss Prime (check out the photo):&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;img src=&#34;1.jpeg&#34; alt=&#34;drawing&#34; width=55%/&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In addition to him, I also charged and pumped Revenant Prime. In short, this was fun.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;tuesday---something-on-tired&#34;&gt;Tuesday - something on tired&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Nothing interesting happened on Tuesday. Unless I came tired after PE.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;wednesday-and-thursday---im-a-sleepy-fly&#34;&gt;Wednesday and Thursday - I&amp;rsquo;m a Sleepy Fly&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;These days, nothing interesting happened (in fact, I am in a hurry to finish the project, because I have little time left, so I am too lazy to remember something).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;friday---something-on-foreign&#34;&gt;Friday - something on foreign&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;At night, the Internet was cut down, but instead of washing the dishes and going to bed, I hung up on my phone until 4 AM.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;saturday---lab-day&#34;&gt;Saturday - Lab Day&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;On Saturday, I decided to go to the story, because there was only one couple. I crossed into the subway with a very beautiful girl who tried to draw my attention to herself (she did it), but I was afraid to come up and get acquainted, because I am a fantastic fool.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;sunday&#34;&gt;Sunday&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;All day I sat and played with a friend from Samara.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;summing-up&#34;&gt;Summing up&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I did not begin to devote more time to study and sleep, but I began to engage in physical development.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Good luck, my dear reader!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Preparation of the report</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/en/post/post6_report-decor/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 30 Apr 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/en/post/post6_report-decor/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;design-rules-in-accordance-with-gost-15-2001-and-gost-71-2003&#34;&gt;Design rules in accordance with GOST 1.5-2001 and GOST 7.1-2003&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The text of the practice report should be typed on a computer in Times New Roman font of 14 pt. (the text is formatted using the Microsoft Word text editor). The font used in the illustrative material (tables and figures) is recommended to be reduced to 12 pt. The line spacing in the main text is one and a half. In the illustrative material, line spacing is recommended to be made single. Page fields must be:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;left field - 30 mm;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;right field - 10 mm;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;upper and lower fields - 20 mm.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Each paragraph must start with a red line. The indent of the paragraph is 12.5 mm. from the left border of the text.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Each section of the report must start with a new page. The name of the structural elements of the report &amp;ldquo;CONTENTS,&amp;rdquo; &amp;ldquo;INTRODUCTION,&amp;rdquo; &amp;ldquo;CONCLUSION,&amp;rdquo; &amp;ldquo;REFERENCES,&amp;rdquo; &amp;ldquo;APPENDIX,&amp;rdquo; as well as section headings should be printed in capital letters and located in the middle of the line. Sections are numbered with Arabic numerals (1, 2, 3). There is no dot at the end of the headings.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Section headings can be bold. Underlining in headings, the use of two or more types of highlighting in headings (for example, italics and bold, italics and another color other than the main text), word wrapping in chapter headings, as well as the use of non-standard characters in the text of the report, and the use of abbreviations in headings are not allowed. In the text of the report, abbreviations of terms are allowed only after the introduction of a meaningful definition of this term. All report pages (except attachments) shall be numbered starting with &amp;ldquo;Introduction,&amp;rdquo; which shall be numbered with 3. Page numbers are located in the center of the bottom of the sheet without a dot.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Illustrative material (tables, figures, formulas) is included in the report for the purpose of clarity of argumentation and justification of the conclusions received by the student. Thus, only material that contributes to a better justification of the conclusions obtained by the student is placed in the main part of the report. Tables, reporting forms and other factual material, which is the initial data on which the study was based, are not included in the main text of the work, but can be placed in the appendix. It is recommended to include tables and figures based on the initial actual data directly in the main text of the report. All illustrative material should, where possible, be placed after the first reference to it in the text.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Illustrations are numbered within sections. An illustration number consists of a section number and an illustration sequence number separated by a period. No dot is placed at the end. If the table is borrowed from a book or article by another author, it should be referenced at the end of the title, taking into account the requirements of these guidelines. It is not allowed to leave free cells in the table columns. If the corresponding data is not available, a dash is put in the column. Units of measurement shall be specified for digital table data. If the table data has different units, then they are indicated in the corresponding headings of the columns or rows of the table. If all table data have the same unit of measurement, then this unit, starting with the preposition &amp;ldquo;c,&amp;rdquo; is given above the table after the name separated by commas (for example, in thousand rubles, in hectares, in sq. M., in percent, etc.).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If necessary, you can move the table to another page. In this case, the following design option is applied. The column (or row) headings of the table are numbered, and the next page does not repeat the text of the headings, but only the corresponding column (row) number. Above the continuation of the table, the words &amp;ldquo;Continuation of Table 1.1&amp;rdquo; are printed on the top right. The table name is not repeated on the new page. It is not allowed to start the table at the bottom of the page if after the name of the table there is only a header part, or a header part plus one or two lines of content, and the main part of the table is on the next sheet. You cannot move a table to the next page if you move one or two rows of table content to the next page. In this case, you should either slightly reduce the font size used in the table so that the table fits entirely on the previous sheet; or slightly increase the spacing between the rows of the table so that the table is more evenly spaced on the pages. Pictures include pictures, diagrams, diagrams, graphs, etc. If a table or figure by volume occupies more than one page, then they must be put in the appendix to the report. The placement of the figures in the report is the same as for other illustrative material, that is, either immediately after the link to it, or on the page closest to this link. Pictures should be placed in the text so that they can be considered without turning the work. All figures shall be numbered within the sections with Arabic numerals: Figure 2.1. Immediately after the designation of the numbering of the picture, a meaningful title follows. The picture number and title are placed at the bottom of the picture, centered on the picture.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Equations and formulas should be separated from the text into a separate line. In formulas, symbols established by the relevant state standards and reflected in the formula format should be used as symbols.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Literature sources used in the process of writing the report are indicated at the end of the work before the application.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;An example of the design of a bibliographic description:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Normative legal acts Constitution of the Russian Federation: official. text. - M.: Marketing, 2017. - 39 p. Family Code of the Russian Federation: [feder. law: adopted by the State. Duma Dec. 8, 1995: as of Jan. 3, 2001]. - St. Petersburg: Staun Country, 2001. - 94 s.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;One-volume book by one author: Glazunov V.A. Spatial mechanisms of parallel structure. M.: Science, 1991. 94 pp.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A one-volume book by two or more authors: Abalakin V.K., Aksenov E.P., Grebenikov E.A., Demin V.G., Ryabov Yu.A. Reference Guide to Celestial Mechanics and Astrodynamics/ed. G.N. Duboshina. M.: Science, 1976. 864 p. Marshak I.S., Doinikov A.S., Zhiltsov V.P., Kirsanov V.P., Rovinsky RE, Schukin L.N., Feigenbaum M.G. Pulsed light sources/under the general. ed. I.S. Marshak. 2nd ed., Revised and add. M.: Energy, 1978. 472 p. Translation book: Sebehey V. Theory of orbits: a limited problem of three bodies: trans. from English/ed. G.N. Duboshin. M.: Science, 1982. 656 с. [Victor G. Szebehely. Theory of Orbits: the Restricted Problem of Three Bodies. New York : Academic Press, 1967.]. Date K.J. Introduction to database systems: translated from English M.: Williams, 2006. 1328 с. [Date C.J. An Introduction to Database Systems. 8th ed. AddisonWesley, 2003. 1024 p.]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Separate volume of the multi-volume edition: Welding and weldable materials: reference book. In 3 vol. 1. Weldability of materials/ed. E.L. Makarov. M.: Metallurgy, 1991. 258 p. Thesis: Pnev A.B. Optical-electronic measuring systems based on quasi-distributed fiber-optic Bragg sensors: dis&amp;hellip;. Candidate of Technology sciences. M., 2008. 176 s.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Thesis abstract: Vishnyakov I.V. Models and methods for assessing commercial banks in conditions of uncertainty: abstract. dis&amp;hellip;. cand. econ. sciences. M., 2002. 15 p. Analytical review: Economics and politics of Russia and neighboring countries: analyte. review, Apr 2007/Ros. acad. sciences, Institute of World Economy and International Relations. M.,: IMEMO, 2007. 39 pp.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Scientific work deposited: Gromov Yu.Yu., Derevuz M.M., Zemskoy N.A., Ivanova O.G., Mosyagina N.G. Algorithm of numerical solution of rigid differential equations/Tambov State Technical University. Tambov, 1999. 8 p. Dep. at VINITI 04.03.1999, No. 669-V1999. Standard: GOST R 517721-2001. Electronic household equipment. Input and output parameters and connection types.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Technical requirements. Tikhanovskaya. 2002- 01-01. M.: Publishing House of Standards, 2001. 27 p. Patent: Chugaeva V.I. Transceiver: Pat. 2187888 Russian Federation. 2002. Bul. No. 23 (2 hours). 3 p.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Article in the periodical: Tchaikovsky M.M., Yadykin I.B. Optimal setting of PID controllers for multi-connected bilinear control objects//Automation and telemechanics. 2009. № 1. S. 130-146. Zvyagin F.V. About one class of orbits in the problems of three and four bodies//Bulletin of MSTU named after N.E. Bauman. Ser. Instrument making. 2010. № 2. S. 105-113. Stankevich I.V., Yakovlev ME, Si Tu Htet. Development of a contact interaction algorithm based on an alternating method//Bulletin of MSTU named after N.E. Bauman. Ser. Natural sciences. 2011. Special. vol. &amp;ldquo;Applied Mathematics.&amp;rdquo; S. 134-141.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Article in the collection: Dvinyaninova G.S. Compliment: Communicative status or strategy in discourse//Social power of language: Sat. scientific. tr. Voronezh, 2001. S. 42-49. Orlik A.G., Kobernik N.V. Obtaining wear-resistant anti-abrasive coatings//Proceedings of MSTU named after N.E. Bauman. 2010. No. 602: Mathematical modeling of complex technical systems. S. 34-38. Article in the ongoing publication: Belova G.D. Some issues of criminal liability for violation of tax legislation//Actual. problems prosecutor. supervision. 2001. No. 5: Prosecutorial supervision of the implementation of criminal and criminal procedure legislation. Organization of the activities of the prosecutor&amp;rsquo;s office. S. 46-49. Painters V.P., Pyatosin L.P. Complex compounds of thorium with diantipyrylmethane//Uchen. West/Perm un-t. 1970. № 207. S. 184-191. Work in the conference materials: Karpenko A.P., Seliverstov E.Yu. Global optimization by the method of swarming particles on GPUs//All-Russia. supercomputer conference &amp;ldquo;Scientific service on the Internet: scalability, parallelism, efficiency&amp;rdquo;: proceedings. M.: Publishing House of Moscow State University, 2009. S. 188-191. Simonov A. Wastewater treatment: design of technical devices//7th regional conference of young researchers of the Volgograd region (Volgograd, May 12-15, 2002): tez. doc. Volgograd, 2002. S. 13-15.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Chapter in the book: Berliner EM, Glazyrina IB, Glazyrin B.E. Automation of individual operations in Word 2000//Office 2000:5 books. in 1: self-taught. 2nd ed., Revised M., 2002. Ch. 14. PP. 281-298. Article in the multivolume edition: Kulakov V.A. Victorian style//BDT. M., 2006. VOL. 5. S. 308-309.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The report does not recommend retelling the content of textbooks, teaching aids, regulatory and special literature. This information should be revised and presented in the content of the work. Direct borrowing from sources without reference to the author or normative document is unacceptable. When using digital data, provisions from official documents, citations and other published materials, the student must indicate the source and make a link in square brackets. Example: [12, p. 34], which means: 12 - source number in the list of references, 34 - page number. The application contains materials that supplement the text of the report. For example, the data used for calculations; intermediate tables and diagrams that influenced the construction of the final tables and figures; intermediate calculations showing the dynamics of the student&amp;rsquo;s evidence development; description of algorithms; tables and figures of non-standard format, etc. Applications are placed in the work after the reference list. Each application is numbered sequentially in Arabic numerals. If the application is more than one page, then it is transferred to another page and at the top is designated as &amp;ldquo;Continuation of the application&amp;hellip;.&amp;rdquo; All appendices shall be referenced in the report text. The location of the appendices at the end of the document should correspond to the order in which they are referenced in the text. Each application starts with a new page. In the upper right corner of the page, the word &amp;ldquo;APPENDIX&amp;rdquo; is indicated and its serial number is placed (for example, &amp;ldquo;APPENDIX 1&amp;rdquo;). Each appendix shall have a title, which shall be indicated on the next line after the word &amp;ldquo;APPENDIX,&amp;rdquo; and this title shall be centered relative to the text. If documents are in large format, they must be stacked in A4 format. In this case, one page of such a non-standard size is numbered as one page of the application (without taking into account its addition).&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Lightweight Markup Languages</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/en/post/post4_markdown/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 20 Apr 2024 23:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/en/post/post4_markdown/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;general-information&#34;&gt;General information&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Lightweight markup languages ​ ​ are used in applications where users can be tricked into reading the original document as well as a properly rendered document. For example, Wikipedia articles are written using a lightweight markup language, wiki text.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Another example is that a person loading a software library may prefer to read documentation in a text editor rather than a web browser.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The main use of these languages is to enter content for a website involving various authors, such as blogs and wikis, for which the only guaranteed interface available to all authors is a simple text field.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;members&#34;&gt;Members&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Markdown&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Org-mode&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;BBCode&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;reStructuredText&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Textile&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Вики-разметка&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;lightweight-languages-for-writing-mathematical-expressions&#34;&gt;Lightweight languages for writing mathematical expressions&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;AsciiMath&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How was my week? Part 2</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/en/post/post3_last-week/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 20 Apr 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/en/post/post3_last-week/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;monday-is-warframe-day&#34;&gt;Monday is Warframe Day&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;On Monday, I finally finished all the tasks for getting Excalibur Umbra (spent 3 days on this) in Warframe. Check out this handsome frame:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;img src=&#34;1.jpeg&#34; alt=&#34;drawing&#34; width=55%/&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Now I&amp;rsquo;m targeting Gauss Prime. Here it is:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;img src=&#34;2.png&#34; alt=&#34;drawing&#34; width=55%/&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;tuesday---something-on-tired&#34;&gt;Tuesday - something on tired&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Nothing interesting happened on Tuesday. Unless I came tired after PE.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;wednesday-and-thursday---im-a-sleepy-fly&#34;&gt;Wednesday and Thursday - I&amp;rsquo;m a sleepy fly&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Not only do you need to get up at 5:20 these days, you also put two controls (mathematical logic and analytic geometry) on thursday.
On Wednesday, after a couple of rides, I went home preparing for the test.
Thursday is doomsday. Firstly, the wire at the station broke in Odintsovo, which is why Dima, Yegor and Lyokha and I sat on Pionerskaya for an hour, but sat cheerfully. Secondly, we wrote the controls, and, it seems, I am very dissatisfied with the angema, because I got frankly fig numbers, which is why I was dumb a lot and decided not everything. I am more or less satisfied with the control matlogue.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;friday---something-on-foreign&#34;&gt;Friday - something on foreign&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Having slept after two difficult days, I served two pairs in foreign languages ​ ​ and went home, where I sat and farmed until 5 AM.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;saturday---lab-day&#34;&gt;Saturday - Lab Day&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Today I sit and make foreheads from 2 PM. I didn&amp;rsquo;t go to history because I don&amp;rsquo;t want to.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;sunday&#34;&gt;Sunday&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The day is not open, buy a subscription for $10 to open this day of the week.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;summing-up&#34;&gt;Summing up&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I did not begin to devote more time to study and sleep, but I began to engage in physical development.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Good luck, my dear reader!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Git Version Management</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/en/post/post2_git/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 20 Mar 2024 23:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/en/post/post2_git/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;about-version-control&#34;&gt;About Version Control&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A version control system is a system that records changes to a file or set of files over time and allows you to return to a specific version later. The software source code will be used as an example for versioning files in this workbook, although you can actually use version control for almost any file type.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;local-version-control-systems&#34;&gt;Local version control systems&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Many people use copying files to a separate directory as a version control method (perhaps even a time-stamped directory, if they are smart enough). This approach is very common because of its simplicity, but it
incredibly highly prone to errors. You can easily forget which directory you are in and accidentally change the wrong file or copy the wrong files you wanted.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In order to solve this problem, programmers long ago developed local VCSs with a simple database that stores records of all changes in files, thereby monitoring revisions.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;img src=&#34;1.png&#34; alt=&#34;drawing&#34; width=55%/&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;centralized-version-control-systems&#34;&gt;Centralized version control systems&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The next major challenge people face is the need to interact with other developers. In order to deal with it, centralized version control systems (Centralized Version Control System, hereinafter CVCS) were developed. Systems such as CVS, Subversion, and Perforce use a single server containing all versions of files, and a number of clients that receive files from this centralized repository. The use of CVCS has been the standard for many years.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This approach has many advantages, especially over local VCSs. For example, all project developers know to a certain extent what each of them is doing. Administrators have complete control over who can do what, and it is much easier to administer CVCS than to operate local databases on each client.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Despite this, this approach also has serious disadvantages. The most obvious disadvantage is a single point of failure represented by a centralized server. If this server fails for an hour, then during this time no one will be able to use version control to save the changes they are working on, and no one will be able to exchange these changes with other developers. If the hard disk on which the central database is stored is damaged, and there are no timely backups, you will lose everything - the entire history of the project, not counting the single repository snapshots that were saved on the local developer machines. Local VCSs suffer from the same problem: when the entire project history is stored in one place, you risk losing everything.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;img src=&#34;2.png&#34; alt=&#34;drawing&#34; width=55%/&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;distributed-version-control-systems&#34;&gt;Distributed version control systems&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is where Distributed Version Control System (DVCS) comes into play. In DVCS (such as Git, Mercurial, Bazaar or Darcs), clients do not just download a snapshot of all files (file status at a certain point in time) - they completely copy the repository. In this case, if one of the servers through which the developers exchanged data dies, any client repository can be copied to another server to continue working. Each copy of the repository is a complete backup of all data.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Moreover, many DVCS can simultaneously interact with several remote repositories, so you can work with different groups of people, applying different approaches at the same time within the same project. This allows you to apply several approaches at once in development, for example, hierarchical models, which is completely impossible in centralized systems.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;3.png&#34; alt=&#34;drawing&#34; width=55%/&gt;&amp;mdash;
title: Управление версиями Git
subtitle: В данной публикации я постараюсь раскрыть вам тему об управлении версиями git.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1 id=&#34;summary-for-listings-and-search-engines&#34;&gt;Summary for listings and search engines&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;summary: В данной публикации я постараюсь раскрыть вам тему об управлении версиями git.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1 id=&#34;link-this-post-with-a-project&#34;&gt;Link this post with a project&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;projects: []&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1 id=&#34;date-published&#34;&gt;Date published&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;date: &amp;lsquo;2024-03-20T23:00:00Z&amp;rsquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1 id=&#34;date-updated&#34;&gt;Date updated&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;lastmod: &amp;lsquo;2024-03-20T23:00:00Z&amp;rsquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1 id=&#34;is-this-an-unpublished-draft&#34;&gt;Is this an unpublished draft?&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;draft: false&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1 id=&#34;show-this-page-in-the-featured-widget&#34;&gt;Show this page in the Featured widget?&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;featured: false&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1 id=&#34;featured-image&#34;&gt;Featured image&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;h1 id=&#34;place-an-image-named-featuredjpgpng-in-this-pages-folder-and-customize-its-options-here&#34;&gt;Place an image named &lt;code&gt;featured.jpg/png&lt;/code&gt; in this page&amp;rsquo;s folder and customize its options here.&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;image:
caption: &amp;lsquo;Image credit: &lt;a href=&#34;https://unsplash.com/photos/CpkOjOcXdUY&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Unsplash&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&amp;rsquo;
focal_point: &amp;rsquo;&#39;
placement: 2
preview_only: false&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;authors:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;admin&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;tags:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Academic&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;categories:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Demo&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;о-системе-контроля-версий&#34;&gt;О системе контроля версий&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Система контроля версий — это система, записывающая изменения в файл или набор файлов в течение времени и позволяющая вернуться позже к определённой версии. Для контроля версий файлов в этой книге в качестве примера будет использоваться исходный код программного обеспечения, хотя на самом деле вы можете использовать контроль версий практически для любых типов файлов.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;локальные-системы-контроля-версий&#34;&gt;Локальные системы контроля версий&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Многие люди в качестве метода контроля версий применяют копирование файлов в отдельный каталог (возможно даже, каталог с отметкой по времени, если они достаточно сообразительны). Данный подход очень распространён из-за его простоты, однако он
невероятно сильно подвержен появлению ошибок. Можно легко забыть в каком каталоге вы находитесь и случайно изменить не тот файл или скопировать не те файлы, которые вы хотели.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Для того, чтобы решить эту проблему, программисты давным-давно разработали локальные VCS с простой базой данных, которая хранит записи о всех изменениях в файлах, осуществляя тем самым контроль ревизий.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;img src=&#34;1.png&#34; alt=&#34;drawing&#34; width=55%/&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;централизованные-системы-контроля-версий&#34;&gt;Централизованные системы контроля версий&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Следующая серьёзная проблема, с которой сталкиваются люди, — это необходимость взаимодействовать с другими разработчиками. Для того, чтобы разобраться с ней, были разработаны централизованные системы контроля версий (Centralized Version Control System, далее CVCS). Такие системы, как CVS, Subversion и Perforce, используют единственный сервер, содержащий все версии файлов, и некоторое количество клиентов, которые получают файлы из этого централизованного хранилища. Применение CVCS являлось стандартом на протяжении многих лет.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Такой подход имеет множество преимуществ, особенно перед локальными VCS. Например, все разработчики проекта в определённой степени знают, чем занимается каждый из них. Администраторы имеют полный контроль над тем, кто и что может делать, и гораздо проще администрировать CVCS, чем оперировать локальными базами данных на каждом клиенте.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Несмотря на это, данный подход тоже имеет серьёзные минусы. Самый очевидный минус — это единая точка отказа, представленная централизованным сервером. Если этот сервер выйдет из строя на час, то в течение этого времени никто не сможет использовать контроль версий для сохранения изменений, над которыми работает, а также никто не сможет обмениваться этими изменениями с другими разработчиками. Если жёсткий диск, на котором хранится центральная БД, повреждён, а своевременные бэкапы отсутствуют, вы потеряете всё — всю историю проекта, не считая единичных снимков репозитория, которые сохранились на локальных машинах разработчиков. Локальные VCS страдают от той же самой проблемы: когда вся история проекта хранится в одном месте, вы рискуете потерять всё.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;img src=&#34;2.png&#34; alt=&#34;drawing&#34; width=55%/&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;распределённые-системы-контроля-версий&#34;&gt;Распределённые системы контроля версий&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Здесь в игру вступают распределённые системы контроля версий (Distributed Version Control System, далее DVCS). В DVCS (таких как Git, Mercurial, Bazaar или Darcs) клиенты не просто скачивают снимок всех файлов (состояние файлов на определённый момент времени) — они полностью копируют репозиторий. В этом случае, если один из серверов, через который разработчики обменивались данными, умрёт, любой клиентский репозиторий может быть скопирован на другой сервер для продолжения работы. Каждая копия репозитория является полным бэкапом всех данных.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Более того, многие DVCS могут одновременно взаимодействовать с несколькими удалёнными репозиториями, благодаря этому вы можете работать с различными группами людей, применяя различные подходы единовременно в рамках одного проекта. Это позволяет применять сразу несколько подходов в разработке, например, иерархические модели, что совершенно невозможно в централизованных системах.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;img src=&#34;3.png&#34; alt=&#34;drawing&#34; width=55%/&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How was my week?</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/en/post/post1_last-week/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 20 Mar 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/en/post/post1_last-week/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;monday-is-bum-day&#34;&gt;Monday is bum day&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;On Mondays, couples are at a distance, so you can relax. I get up at 9 AM, connect to the lesson, and I myself go to the kitchen for food. After a hearty breakfast, you can play. I make the sound of the game quieter and calmly farm in the wonderful game Warfame.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;img src=&#34;1.png&#34; alt=&#34;drawing&#34; width=55%/&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After that, I clean the apartment and sit down at the farm again.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;tuesday---something-on-sports&#34;&gt;Tuesday - something on sports&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;On Tuesday, we have only PE at 3 PM. Of course, there is still a lecture on computer algebra, but who would wake up to this lecture. Because PE in another building is also 15, and I live 2 hours round trip, then I have to leave the house at 12 AM. The main problem is that at this time we have a change of trains, which is why I cannot use this wonderful mode of transport in our city. I have to go on the 1055 bus, which goes to Odintsovo, from where I am already going on the electronic. So many people enter this bus that, sometimes, it seems that the metal will not stand it, and the bus will simply burst. Among this number of people, a large share is occupied by pensioners who always need to go to the market, although this can be done on other days of the week, but okay, it&amp;rsquo;s not for me to decide.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;img src=&#34;2.jpeg&#34; alt=&#34;drawing&#34; width=55%/&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I guessed up to one trick: you have to sit mainly from the edge in order to be &amp;ldquo;locked&amp;rdquo; and simply physically cannot give way.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Then PE: a warm-up, after which the legs hurt, and then playing basket, which worsen the situation.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;By 8 PM I come home, have dinner, play a little and mentally prepare to get up at 5 AM in the morning.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;img src=&#34;3.jpeg&#34; alt=&#34;drawing&#34; width=55%/&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;who-came-up-with-wednesday-and-thursday&#34;&gt;Who came up with Wednesday and Thursday&amp;hellip;&amp;hellip;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In short, these are the only two days when couples start at 9 AM and I get up at 5 AM. It is on these days that I cross the sos with my friends from school, with whom I have the same schedule. Basically, this is Dima, sometimes Yegor also joins us. True, they need to be at the university by 8:30, so I&amp;rsquo;m going with them on the train at 6:59, which is why I come 30, and sometimes 40, minutes earlier.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I sleep for 3-4 hours these days.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;img src=&#34;4.jpeg&#34; alt=&#34;drawing&#34; width=55%/&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;friday&#34;&gt;Friday!!!&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;On this day, I sleep off after the previous two days. Of the pairs for Friday: English and German - I don&amp;rsquo;t want to go, but I have to. I go to the university by 13:30, study until 16:20, and then I go home, where I can sit down to play for hours until 5 AM, or I can do laboratory work on the os-intro, but I usually do it on Saturday.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;saturday---lab-day&#34;&gt;Saturday - Lab Day&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I, in theory, should appear on the story, but I do it very rarely.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The moment is coming to make foreheads. I close myself in my room and record screencasts.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After 23:59 I am free, so again I can play on computer for hours until 5 AM.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;sunday-is-the-day-of-oblivion&#34;&gt;Sunday is the day of oblivion&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;On this day, I am as divorced from the university as possible, so there is a feeling that I am not studying anywhere and I dreamed of it all, but Sunday ends and I return to the harsh reality of the school week.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;img src=&#34;5.jpeg&#34; alt=&#34;drawing&#34; width=55%/&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;summing-up&#34;&gt;Summing up&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is the week I get. Soon I plan to devote more time to study and healthy sleep.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Good luck, my dear reader!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
